MD Najrul Islam **Sumon**

REACT DEVELOPER

45/1, Hazipara, Rampura, Dhaka - 1217, Rep. of BANGLADESH

© (+880) 1845393505 | M nazrul2517@gmail.com | ⊕najrulislam | ♠najrul04 | ♠najrul04

SUMMARY

I'm an experienced React developer with a strong foundation in JavaScript, ReactJS, Redux, NextJS, and TailwindCSS. I possess excellent adaptability and can work efficiently in both team and independent work environment, with a strong drive to continuously learn and master emerging technologies.

TECHNICAL SKILLS_

Expertise: HTML5, CSS3, Tailwind CSS, Bootstrap5, JavaScript, ES6, React JS, GitHub, React Router **Fundamentals:** TypeScript, Node JS, Express JS, NoSQL, Firebase, MongoDB, Next JS, Redux, RestAPI, Wordpress, PHP, jQuery, Figma

EXPERIENCE

FRONT END DEVELOPER, INVENT

JAN 2023 - PRESENT

- Build and design React web app from the scratch to give the company an online existence for potential customers to reach.
- Implement Firebase authentication system with 10,000 authentication request such as email/password, Phone authentication, Third-party authentication per day for free and 100,000 per month for free.
- Create with a library of JavaScript named React JS because of its potential to reuse components which makes the code and website easy to maintain.
- Ensure easy and fast coding with maximum customization options by using Tailwind CSS and raw CSS to develop a responsive website to kept the code clean and easily manageable.
- By utilizing React Router, a private routing system was implemented to ensure ease of editing, reliability and maintainability.
- Implement Node JS and its framework Express JS for the backend technology, data storage is achieved for using MongoDB.

WEB DEVELOPER, Vector Design US, Inc.

JAN 2022 – DEC 2022

- Built the website using WordPress and page builder Elementor for more than 20,000 users.
- Prepared website update proposals to presents to manager, provide technical support to clients and writing code using HTML and CSS.
- Managed a user guide to help and understand site features and management of the websites.
- Updated website as instructed by the company and introduce new features and contents
- Managed comments from visitors, including private emails and comments posted on the site.
- Introduced new plug-ins and extensions to make the website more usable and interactive in order to have better user experience.

EDUCATION

BIST (Bangladesh Institute of Science and Technology)

National University of Bangladesh

Bachelor in Business Administration (Marketing)

JUN. 2016 - DEC. 2020

Programming Hero

Complete Web Development Certificate 2021 in 24 weeks

JUN. 2021 - NOV. 2021

freeCodeCamp

Responsive Web Design JavaScript Algorithms and Data Structures JUN. 2021 MAR. 2023

LANGUAGE_

English, Bengali